Christian McFarland

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

📞 (905) 746-2567 | 🖂 christianmcfa@gmail.com | 🏶 christianmcfarland.vercel.app | 🕠 christianmcfar | in christian-mcfarland

Summary ____

Software developer with a passion for crafting software that offers intuitive user experiences. Driven to create designs optimized for efficient and aesthetic interfaces to facilitate collaborative team projects and quickly iterate towards reaching a common goal. Motivated to help others learn and succeed by breaking down difficult problems into manageable pieces.

Experience _____

Moneris Etobicoke, ON, Canada

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Feb. 2020 - Nov. 2023

- Developed a transaction simulator for QA testing capable of simulating 20k transactions at 50/sec using React, Redux, PHP for CRUD API, SQL, and pm2 —under consideration for external licensing
- Developed a mobile app featuring interactive and customizable data visualization to allow teams to effectively monitor system statistics to prevent and address issues in real-time. Employed Native React for Android and iOS platforms, Parse/Express server, MongoDB for database, and Expo for rapid development to iOS
- Contributed to the redesign of a Terminal Management System by modernizing the UI to facilitate remote management of terminal options and parameters using React, PHP, SQL, and Figma to pitch project designs. Slated to replace legacy system for all Moneris terminals and merchants by 2024
- Developed a mapping tool (MONMAP) displaying routes between over 300k terminal points as scalable clusters using Mapbox API, PostgreSOL and clusterbuster tile server
- Assisted with the hiring and mentoring of a new team member, providing guidance and technical support to enable them to contribute fully to the success of our team

Manulife Financial Kitchener, ON, Canada

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/ BUSINESS SYSTEM ANALYST

May 2016 - Sept. 2017

- Took on developer responsibilities to completely rewrite legacy application used by the call center to quickly access and change customer information during calls using C#, ASP.NET, XML, WiX, and SQL
- Developed and implemented a file system management tool using PowerShell and shell scripting to automate the cleaning and organization of large file systems, resulting in improved efficiency and time savings
- Worked with SQL to extract claims data and scraped incident engagement time to create representation used in 2016 incident report showing statistics of time saved from initial incident to point of recovery from previous years
- Won Red Lab Co-op Innovation Challenge by designing prototype image processing application to solve a Manulife business need. Meet with potential users and clients to determine scope and use cases for possible future Manulife application

Skills ____

Languages JavaScript, PHP, SQL, C#, C++, Java, Python, CSS, HTML

Frameworks React, React Native, .NET Core

Others JIRA, SVN, VS Code, WSL/Linux, Expo, GitHub/Lab, Vercel, Heroku, Node.js, Visual Studio, Figma, PowerShell

Education

Wilfrid Laurier University

Waterloo, ON, Canada

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN HONOURS COMPUTER SCIENCE

May 2019

• Professional Experience Program, Completed at Manulife Financial — May 2016 - Sept 2017